welcome to the seventh episode of BC
under the hood Series so when um when we
design new features at at Microsoft and
and for business Central we spend a lot
of time writing code writing tests um
doing manual test and also fixing box
obviously but there's also another
aspect of Designing new featur fees
which is the your user interface and the
user experience and today with me have
yakob yakob this is this is your area um
so tell us a little bit about what
what's your role in the in the business
Central engineering team and um what
what do you actually work with thank you
Vincent I'd love to um and thanks for
inviting me it's an honor to sit in this
chair knowing sort of who else has been
sitting here telling about business
Central so so thanks a lot um yes so I'm
yinda and I'm leading the business
Central design team and what we do uh
quickly stated is that we're working
with the engineering teams and the
program managers to design and implement
the features that goes into uh business
Central so that means the the visual
appearance um the interaction ways and
the whole sort of how it works uh in a
in a given area of business Central so
that's what you call user experience or
ux and and UI so so these are the terms
that we usually use right UI for um the
actual graphical design and the the
pixels right and and ux for user
experience yes so so the user interface
is the the the actual thing you see you
look at the thing that is being designed
and the user experience is what sort of
uh happens around that user interface
and the distinction is sometimes po
because the user interface is not just
uh it's of course serving up the data
and allowing users to work with business
Central but to have a good user
experience you also need to provide the
uh documentation uh uh the whole uh way
that users get to to discover the
product discover the features and so on
so user experience is a much broader
concept than the user interface which is
literally just what you see on the
screen and that you click on so it's
actually just a user user interface is
just a subset of it and the graphical
design is is but the the user experience
and the graphical design are very
connected right yes but it's kind of a
subset of of the whole thing yes so so
um the user interface lets users access
business Central and and it is a visual
design so it has to look attractive uh
and it is an interaction design it means
that when you click a button something
has to happen uh and when you click two
buttons next after each other it has to
sort of connect logically conceptually
uh so there's a lot of ways where you
can look at the user experience and
break down what it's part of but user
interface is OB sort of the the main
thing that is being designed so what so
what is the usual process when uh we
design a new feature so how at which at
what stage do you get involved and what
what do you do what's what's your what's
your role in what's what's your what's
your part in in in a new feature design
yes I think we we um we could talk a lot
about sort of that topic alone but just
to to sort of paraphrase it a little bit
then we have some features where um we
have a a long period where uh the the
feature is being uh sort of
conceptualized understood and and
researched uh and when we are part of
that feature and the prime example there
would be something like the onboarding
project which was a multi uh um release
investment where we gradually build out
those features and we had a a a somewhat
long period leading up to that to
understand what what is onboarding about
so so that is I mean that literally took
multiple releases to to research and
design and Implement and then we have
sort of smaller features like the other
example I will we can talk about later
is the what is now the company switcher
where you can go in and you can switch
between the different companies and
business Central that was a much shorter
period of time sort of from the idea
that we wanted to do something to the
research through the design to the
shipping was done in in a much shorter
time so it really depends on what kind
of feature and what kind of investment
we are with putting in there but
generally speaking we try to get
involved as early as possible uh with
with with sort of the key Investments so
we can do our sort of due diligence in
terms of understanding that
uh who is the audience for this feature
um what is the problem we're solving uh
have several stages of the mockups and
and red lines I can also Show an example
of that and then the the implementation
phase uh where we also involved in in
overseeing that um that it is being
living up to the intentions and often Al
also catching stuff that wasn't
discovered early on so so I mean
Nobody's Perfect so I mean as you
perfectly know we discover stuff along
the way that means we have to adjust
plans and that's sort of just how
software development works so you you
involved from Al on on the big design
the big feature multi- relases features
you know from from the conceptual
Inception of things but also in smaller
areas smaller features like yes and so
and you are as you say you were involved
at all and many many stages of of the
design process um so so when uh is there
is there a set of rules you're are using
or reference so you want when you you to
make these designs um is there you know
somewhere you can look up uh as a
reference yeah yeah I almost wish there
was sort of a book of solutions where
you could look in and just pull out the
one and go ahead um and
obviously um to meet users uh
expectations uh we need to factor in
their con ceptions of the world so I
would say that that the first thing
we're looking at is we're trying to
understand where is the users coming
from and that requires for you to know
actually our users pretty well yes so a
good part of our work is uh working with
users both customers and partners to
understand their perspective of things
and when we talk about a business
Central uh feature we are obviously a
lot of the time talking about business
Central users so when we are having a
new feature we try to say look at so
which of the use business Central users
are going to use this feature how are
they uh sort of uh understanding
business Central and we try to align
with their conception so I would say the
first big sort of uh light post for us
when we design a feature is sort of the
understandings that the users are going
to have then being part of Microsoft
there's a whole sort of body of design
and Concepts that um are coming from uh
not necessarily sort of a central Source
but there's a lot of work in Microsoft
going on that also establish patterns
and interaction paradigms and visuals
and branding and so on that's a way to
align across products right yes exactly
so we don't have like word looks in way
and then business Central will look
totally different confusing the users
right exactly the the the the the the um
sort of the Mantra of one Microsoft also
means that when users go into one
Microsoft products and are trying and
doing something then they uh have the
advantage that when they come to another
Microsoft product if they can use the
same pattern or Paradigm even down to
the same icon for I mean a common
concept like sharing it would be
difficult if in one program from
Microsoft the share icon look one way
and in another program it looked uh in
another way so that would not have that
recognition so we we're looking heavily
at other Microsoft products and
standards and guidelines to guide how we
are designing business Central um and in
terms of what we call the design
language simply how what kind of styling
do you choose for business Central we
are adhering to what is known as the
fluent design language which is
Microsoft sort of official this this is
a is it is it a Microsoft uh kind of
developed design language for all
Microsoft products yes so so people can
find it online there's a search just
search for fluent design language and
you can find style guides and and
widgets for the fluent uh design
language we can put links in the
description yeah yep and and it's a
fully encompassing design language for
all the stuff you would expect in a user
uh interface like drop downs and input
fields and radio buttons and what have
you and that's sort of ions colors all
that is defined or uh yes um so so of
course we are um uh we are giving the
business Central products the business
Central sort of treatment in the sense
that given our fantastic uh sort of um
Legacy of of business Central there's a
lot of the patterns and and ways of
working that we have brought
along it's important our user when they
see the product they recognize it at
business Central as well right they
don't look when they don't think oh
maybe it's word or Excel or something
but like everybody you know Excel is
like the green and word like the blue
you know and uh so what what's business
Central yes so so we have uh in terms of
color we have this sort of teal brand um
but people often say that Excel and Word
and PowerPoint are similar but really
it's it's an illusion right because if
you look at those programs they do a lot
of things differently for good reasons
because one is for presentation the
other is for word processing and the
second is for for spreadsheet and BC is
ANP product business Central is for
another thing so so we are definitely
aligning where it makes sense and and we
are also in terms of uh aligning with
Microsoft Office is a huge inspiration
for us in terms of how things should
work and act um but we cannot just pull
the answers from office because we have
to adjust it to what are users actually
doing in business Central uh what are
the task they have and they are not
creating presentations in business
Central they are not sort of writing
letters in business Central they are
doing Erp tasks so obviously we we look
heavily and that would be sort of the
third pillar of of of what we're looking
at is simply what are what tasks are
users doing what do we need to do to
make business Central successful uh uh
sorry to make our users successful in
business
Central so so I want to talk a little
bit about figb you you use that a lot in
your team right can you can you tell us
a little bit what what that is and how
how use it or maybe you know some our uh
you know users are familiar with it but
uh yes uh so so figma is a design tool
um it has uh it's sort of the the the
preferred choice for many Microsoft
teams these days but it's not a
Microsoft tool is it it's not a
Microsoft tool it's actually recently uh
acquired by Adobe so so these days it's
an adobe tool um and it's it's
interesting with Adobe because a lot of
people obviously know illustrator and
Photoshop and acrobat and sort of the
Adobe portfolio so figma is was was a
nice sort of complement to their sort of
a modern complement um and it is but it
is at the end of the day not doing much
different from what maybe illustrator uh
did in the past and in the past
literally we were using illustrate all
the time uh so these design tools sort
of change and right now figma is a great
tool for most UI design so what can you
do with it so it is a uh it's a drawing
package at the end of the day um so it
let you design on a canvas similar to
what illustrator offered uh draw
elements put boxes and and their killer
feature if you will for why they got
successful was that they handled
multi-user editing very well from from
day one so so even in a last design team
if you are working on something together
then everybody I mean uh being able to
work in the same document it sounds
simple to say today I mean how could it
ever be different but you have to go
long back in time before we were sort of
creating files and sharing files and
opening and this is V1 and this is V2
and final final and all that so so figma
is sort of the preferred tool for design
teams uh certainly in Microsoft and in
other many other places so being a maybe
more on the development side or code
writing side than you are I think you
know I've seen some of these figmas and
and and sometimes you know so so you as
you say you create them usually early in
the in the development process so at an
early stage and um and sometimes it's a
little bit you know it it sets
expectations High because you can I mean
you must admit it's easier to um design
a feature in in in a way with thi Mass
you you can draw pretty much what you
want but sometimes you end up in this uh
you know we we I know you and I have had
some uh interaction in the past where
you know you you you come up with
something and then uh and then you then
when we actually to have to implement it
then realize it's actually more
expensive than uh in terms of you know
uh time and and and and maybe also
complexity um but but usually we I think
we're having you know you're having a
good dialogue with the with our
developers and and so so how my question
I guess is how far do you get you know
when you come with the first FC mass and
when the feature ends up being
implemented you know uh how much uh does
the actual feature ends up diverging
from the original figma you created
right no I I think there two parts to
what you say there one is clearly that
where you start is usually not where you
end up MH I mean and and that is sort of
because the nature of software
development and and sort of navigating
in this sort of Erp space and building
these features are I mean relatively
complex so the initial idea about what
this should do and then where it ends up
after working with Engineers PMS uh
doing use research uh and factoring all
that up into the solution means that
that you often end up in another place
than than you thought you would which is
uh you could say the right place to end
up because at that point in time you
have factored in input from all these
peoples and all these insights and I
have an example of that we can also look
at um so that is one side of it that
that that the uh you simply get wiser
along the process and you need to change
to accommodate all this input the other
part is then um being in figma or any
design tool you choose um and and as I
mentioned we have used illustrator we
have used Invision we have used in
design there's a bunch of packages even
PowerPoint I mean PowerPoint is still
very sort of low cost in terms of
creating something where you can click
through and you can create an illusion
of an experience that people can react
to uh and that is really sort of the the
secret Source in in in sort of in ux and
ux design is that you need to let user
ERS understand where you are wanting to
take them and and it's very effective to
show users at a journey or a click
through and they can instantly react to
that it's much harder in words to
describe first you go to this screen and
then there's a button and then you go to
that screen and then there's another
button it's very hard for for most
people to visualize that um and if you
put them in front of a figma where it's
just a mockup of the actual experience
or a PowerPoint your favorite tool you
can simulate what they would experience
and most people will react to it and and
that is a I mean uh what we do for a
living so to say we we are selling the
vision of how great this could be and
then um when when reality hits often we
need to scale down some Ambitions and we
can maybe uh do it in another way
mitigate it but it's very important as a
design team to put out these ideas or
visions of how great it could be to
inspire uh people also I mean inspire
people in your role of the organization
to say hey this is actually super cool
let's see if we can do that and then at
the end of the day the what we ship is
again as I mentioned before sort of
accommodating a lot of different
requirements so when you compare the two
the vision to what we're actually
shipping you sometimes say ah but but
then there's a next release and a next
release how that so I think you've also
seen exactly so with some of the recent
AI features the the uh the prom dialogue
for for example um our initial version
V1 was very sort of limited but then we
have continued building it out so today
it's the I would say the the best tool
to build co-pilot features for for
business Central and we can put co-pilot
actions and so on we have the whole sort
of foundation in place for delivering
great co-pilot features and that's um
that is uh that has certainly
accommodated a lot of different
requirements along the way so so I would
say it's even better now in the product
than it was in the initial sketches so
that also sometimes happens so you talk
about you talk you mentioned several
times the user testing yeah so um so
you're actually doing uh you're having
like real users from from The Real World
coming are they coming here at Microsoft
and and you show them some how does it
work tell us a little bit about it you
show them some early version of products
and and see how they react um yes all of
the above yeah yeah yeah so are you
sitting like behind a you know oneway
mirror or something is that I know we
have a room like that here uh so do you
use it so um let me first say that that
we call ourselves a design team um but
design team actually means we also doing
a lot of user research so we should
rightfully say the ux design and
research team it just gets so long so in
in in a practical terms Des sign sort of
encompasses everything you need to do to
deliver uh this uh these features from a
design side so the user research part is
typically in two buckets there are what
we call the generative research where
you basically just go out to customers
partners and observe a problem or
challenge or just work practice um and
we call it generative research because
it is sort of it is not sort of
necessarily answering a particular
question it's more generating maybe a
set of questions how could this be
better how could this this be more
interesting and then uh later in the
process when you have something you have
designed and and you want to find out
how how will this UI design work how
will this and that work in the hands of
users then you go also out to customers
also as a research activity more sort of
with a evaluative perspective where you
want to you you're literally going to
the party with something under your arm
and you want to see Half Baked or some
some as early as you can do it typically
because it's it's much cheaper to change
a PowerPoint than it is to to change
something that you have coded so the
more discoveries you can do before you
put stuff into code is usually
better so to to have these feedback
loops and inside Loops yes we are
engaging uh customers and and and
partners and and it happens these days I
mean as you would expect mostly online
okay so in in the old days uh it would
be that we had a special lab on on site
here with a one-way uh glass and so why
why why is the oneway glass what's the
purpose of it the purpose like it looks
like an interrogation room in the movies
right yes and and that's a bad uh um
sort of feeling if people feel they're
being interrogated they being watched
for for sure yes and that was exactly
the problem what typically happened in
the past at least was that you would
have someone who was your participant
someone you wanted to give you feedback
and you want to make them feel
comfortable mhm you you you don't want
to have sort of an exam kind of
situation where they feel they are being
T them over the shoulder for every time
they click on something that that's what
you don't want so so you wanted to
create sort of a an informal situation
where they could give you feedback on
your design and be comfortable with that
even give you critical feedback which is
also super hard if you consider sort of
the situation they're in and to avoid
them feeling observed and to avoid them
feeling like they were at an exam you
typically wanted them to be just talking
to one person so so I mean if you were
my test uh uh person I would be sort of
sitting and having a conversation like
us and we would have the screen and we
would sort of talk about the software
and and if there were sort of 10 people
in the room at the same time observing
you uh then you would not feel relaxed
uh so it it was back in the days an
attempt to to to create a more natural
setting I'm not sure they achieved that
but but that was the idea but coming
back to today um as you would expect
most has happens online okay so so the
way we run these what we call lab
studies is not really in a lab it is uh
on on teams or some specialized tools
where fundamentally it works the same
way as if you had invited people in so
you may a set up a meeting with someone
who has signed up to this um maybe
recruited for from our user insights
panel that we have um for people who are
helping us try out business Central
early on um and then you you have a
typically onetoone or or with a co-
colleague and um give them a link to the
software they're sharing their screen
you ask them to to solve a particular
task in business Central and you don't
give them how to do it you want them
typically to discover how to do it so
we're building the product to be as so
and the features to be as discoverable
as possible like that that's basically
for some features that we don't you
don't need like an to read you don't
need to read the documentation for for
some features you shouldn't be able you
shouldn't have to is that that's a goal
for some of the features for some of the
features yes exactly you said it there
um depending on the feature it will uh
determine how you want to test it
because obviously if you are designing
someone like the onboarding stuff of the
onboarding experience obviously we
couldn't expect that people being
unboarded trying business Central For
the First Time new business Central so
when when you're testing onboarding
features you pretty much have to accept
that they don't know business
Central to be highly discoverable it has
to be discoverable by someone who
doesn't know where us should it to look
in business Central but with another
feature we build the um uh the analysis
mode for for gits we were not designing
that for users who were new to business
Central that yeah that this this for
experienced users and it is mostly for
experienced users who who come to to
have the need to do these kind of
analysis so when we were recruiting
users to try that particular features we
were recruiting users who had experience
with business Central when we were
recruiting people to try onboarding we
were recruiting folks that didn't know
business Central so so it also about
sort of connecting and making sort of
the uh recruit the people that are relev
for the feature that you designing so
you had some uh some examples you wanted
to show us um yes let's look at for
example the analysis mode first to to
and you mentioned this about um the
mockups versus what we actually ship um
so here is an example uh of on the left
hand side the the mock up from uh the
PowerPoint in this case we we when we
built when we were uh sort of trying out
before theature got implemented before
anyone wrote any code this um we
designed how would it be to use if the
feature was in the product and this was
the version on the left hand side that
we tested with users and you can see
here if you compare to the right hand
side that is the version that you
actually shipped that initially we had
the idea that the Taps of the analysis
would be at the bottom of the page and
then uh uh we would have the normal
action bar at the top of the page and in
user testing this turned out to be not a
great solution because uh users even
experienced users of business Central
would Overlook the tabs in the buttom
mhm so we can speculate why they were
overlooking it um but you ended up
moving them at the top then but at the
end of the day the the solution we opted
for words to say well let's put the the
tabs at the top of the page and that
tested very well with users so so that
was a one very concrete example uh uh
and and um if if I mean there was a lot
of debates and speculations why these
tabs were not being noticed um but at
the end of the day we can't go forward
with a feature where more than half of
the test participants were not noticing
these tabs here so so they came at the
top so we have we have that level of
control on the UI because we are
Microsoft designed the UI but but our
partners can't control it that much I'll
get back to that but we I think we need
to talk a little bit about that let's
let's let's save it for for the end yes
and and quickly stated that is why it's
so important that we get these decisions
right exactly for that reason yes
another example I wanted to also show uh
so where does this feature start and
where did it end up was a compan exactly
the company switcher so on the left hand
side is the PowerPoint mockup we created
and on the right hand side is what we're
actually shipping and apart from I mean
the the the the way that we are using
icons and so on and you can see that it
is pretty close in conceptual side
there's a list of companies but two
important things happened along the way
that sort of radically changed this
feature and and is a good example of
what we are learning along the way and
was this once one one was
that this notion of environments that
some customers have is that they have
access to multiple environments so along
the way we said well this is not
actually a company switcher what users
want here is an environment and Company
switcher so there an envir more than an
environment switching exactly because
when when when customers are having
access to more environments uh then
before this feature it was super hard
for them actually to discover the other
environments and if they wanted to
switch from company in one environment
to a company in another environment that
was next to Impossible unless you had a
sort of URL you could click and knew how
to do it m so this started as a
relatively simple feature how difficult
can it be to switch company to actually
just a drop down of some kind exactly to
actually be a pretty complex features
that involved platform teams uh and and
client teams of course to make sure that
that we were able to know which
environments were available to each of
these users here and then factor that
into the UI and it also is an example of
how we want it to align with how
Microsoft does it because what is known
as the environment um uh selector at the
top of the app of of the app bar you can
see it's here on the right hand side
says environment that was a pattern that
was already existing in other Microsoft
products such as so such as power all
the Power Platform enir platform dat
based exactly so when we ended up saying
well this is also about environments
then clearly we didn't want to design an
environment selector that was done in
another way than people would expect it
so so we ended up sort of aligning with
with how you trigger that and to make
that concrete I can just show you here
the the mo two mockups that we ended up
not doing one on the left hand side you
can see there's an available company's
link we decided not to do that uh and we
decided also not to do the other idea we
had where there was a a tool tip on the
company indicator to switch company the
moment we realized that selecting
company and environment through the app
bar would be the right way to align we
went that wave all out all in it seems
to be a simple feature but I it shows
that uh turns out to be a little more uh
involved than you would you would think
right yes uh as as you also perfectly
know when you open uh some of these
areas it is often sort of a p Pandora's
box of of requirements from customers
Partners internal teams and so on and it
has it all has to come together in a in
a user interface when I used to work
work in the class team we work we work
together quite a lot and I used to be
you know always impressed how you would
be able patient you were with because
the thing with UI and ux that a lot of
people as opposed to other things
everybody thinks they're experts but
clearly a lot of people are not and
everybody has an opinion on you know
which color should be how much spacing
they should be there but Mo most of the
time you working with you I came to
realize how much complexity there is and
how much science there is also into all
these things and uh and and
you know I think it's best to rely on
Experts like you to you know make these
decisions rather than trying to you know
have an have an opinion on you know
which color it should be right thank you
for for the
confidence Vincent I hope I I can live
up to that but but clearly people have
opinions for good reasons because uh
when we were working with the engineers
they obviously have good opinions and we
need to factor that into it so I think
about it more as aligning and
accommodating all these different
opinions and require ments and and then
of course there are areas where um I
mean colors uh where um it can come
across as more subjective but even that
when you look into it is also a complex
mix of brand considerations
accessibility requirements and so on so
not even color is sort of a a place
where you can just pick a random choice
and and go with it because uh uh it will
either sort of not be on brand uh or it
will create problems in terms of
combinations when when people are color
blind and and colors are being confirmed
so um I think my work is I I I love what
we're doing and but I think really about
it as as trying to accommodate all these
requirements and opinions uh and and
make sure that we're designing on the
best possible sort of foundation of of
and insights for that so how about red
lines do you have an example of red
lines yes if we continue in the deck
here um I can just Qui show here also an
example from onboarding um this is a
very early mockup for our onboarding
screen so if our viewers don't recognize
it is because this was never built okay
this is an example of a screen where we
said this was um a good initial idea but
we ended up saying that um this
experience where we were sort of pretty
much taking over the whole screen right
off the bat when users came into
business Central that was not a good
solution because a lot of users we found
would look to how can I explore business
Central before digging into these uh
onboarding experience kind of too
invasive in a way it was too modal
because it was sort of required that you
that you did that before you could start
using business Central so uh you will
recognize this screen this is sort of
the banner where users can decide to
engage with a banner but they can also
decide to just navigate business Central
try something else and then when they
ready for it they can open this
checklist and again this is being
presented in a way that's totally
optional so if they don't want to do
this they can still use business Central
on the side and and close it also so
your question about red lines I took
some examples here of of what we call
red lines and they're called red lines
because you can see it is the UI and
then there are sort of red annotations
uh with kind of an
overlay the design you your team produce
exactly so this is produced in fig mhm
so so this is my my great team members
who are very skilled at figma much more
than I am who are um pretty uh much
documenting uh at a at a very precise uh
level of detail that is needed to
actually go and implement this so it's
all down to the font side the margin
size the spacing between the different
elements all these things yes and and
you give that to the developers and then
they they can they have to implement
that yes so so there is a bit more
clever handoff these days from figma to
developers so so they don't need
necessarily to go and read on the the
little red text here we can actually
hand um uh sort of it off in a digital
form so they can take over the CSS from
figma directly so it's become little
more smooth but at the end of the day
this is sort of the the the
specification uh and it goes into
sometimes to many sort of a surprising
uh level of details because what we have
to do here is also to test how will this
react when suddenly more text appears in
these here so we are we are making tests
of how will these components react when
other contents come into it and as you
know uh we also have to look at
localization so business Central is
being available in a lot of languages
and um that's also a challenge yeah
which means that the content that we are
designing for is not actually known at
the point in time where we are designing
the component so we need to make sure
that all the components we design are
flexible in their sizing uh so when it
scales up or down that the TCH still
flows and looks uh reasonable so so that
is um that is a you could say the final
stage of the design process is that we
are producing the design specification
at this level of detail and that is
being used as the um uh sort of the the
the check or the rule book if you will
for uh okay when when we look at this in
the product is it correct is it aligned
is the margin correct and so on if any
doubt is there then this is where we can
go and check what what was the intention
so sort of to sum it up it's all about
getting from the design intention that
we are establishing together with app
PMS uh and and client PMs and the
engineer leads and so on and all the way
down to the final product where where
that intention hopefully sort of is is
visible so that brings me to I think
it's going to be the last question but I
think it's an important one so we when
you show all this that you we have a lot
of control of these uis I mentioned
before you can we can go on the pixel
label and adjust these things but but
business Central is not you know as
opposed maybe to other type of
programming when when our partners
develop their features they don't have
that level of control we kind of have
decided uh we have decided a lot of uh
we made a lot of decision about the UI
and how it's going to be so they just
Express the basically what they want uh
in a page but they don't go and adjust
the pixels and decide the size of the
buttons and all these things so so what
advice would you would you give to our
partners and developers when uh in terms
of ux and and and design of their
feature when they go you know is there
anything you you would recommend they
should do uh at at their level they
cannot control where they place the
different elements and how they look
like or even how they behave but is
there things they they should be aware
of um in know to get uh to to have a
great user experience for for their
users of their
features yes there there certainly some
aspects to that and and first let me say
that I'm I'm I'm so amazed by what our
partners uh and community in generally
are achieving with business Central I'm
I'm I'm literally Blown Away about the
creativity and and Ingenuity of of of of
the solutions I'm seeing at directions
and and other conferences so so so I'm
I'm I'm totally confident that our
partners are making the right calls in
terms of how they are designing for
business Central um and uh we are
working hard to make it possible for
them and for for partners in general to
do the customizations that they need to
do to deliver a great experience to
their customers uh and that is sort of
our priority number one that our
customers get Solutions based business
Central that is the best you can have um
and we are doing that by um
standardizing I mean we are
standardizing how should a certain page
type work and look um and we are doing
it by reducing flexibility and and that
is sort of where the the the where it
can sometimes get complicated with
business Central because we are um
providing a uh spectrum of flexibility
and if you stay within that spectrum of
flexibility in terms of then then then
you have a a good time with with
business Central and the problem is of
course when you want to do something
that business Central is not supporting
yeah then suddenly it gets super
complicated MH but I think it's useful
to uh think about and I know that that
that people know this already of course
if you go and build a power app for
example to do the same thing that a
business Central card page can do it
will be a lot of work mhm right you will
have to take care of a lot of stuff on
your own if you were to build uh a a
page as complex as a standard car page
bus there's a lot of functionality build
in the car page you get for free
basically by just saying I just want a
page and then you just get it and yes so
so I think the tradeoff when you're
building for business Central is that
you you trade off some
flexibility uh but you get a lot of
behaviors and and and translations and
not to mention security and and so on uh
as that so so in some situations that
tradeoff uh is easy to establish because
you you don't need the flexibility for a
certain case if you have to create a
highly customized solution for a
customer then I would certainly look at
Power app I mean is this scenario worth
doing a power app for instead of trying
to to uh um to hack the way around
business ation between powerups and
business Central anyway yes I I think
the story around what you can do to
connect business Central data to other
places is is a super story so that is
sometimes the right uh tradeoff to make
all right thank you yob that was really
interesting another aspect of U how we
build business Central um thank you for
watching I hope you enjoy this episodes